[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon and welcome
&gt;&gt; 大家下午好
everybody to our session, what's
欢迎来到我们的会场
new in user notifications.
一起看一下 用户通知的一些更新
I'm Kritarth Jain [inaudible] on
我叫 Kritarth Jain [ 音质不清晰 ]
the iOS notifications team, and
是 iOS 用户通知团队的一名工程师
we're very excited to be back at
很高兴回到 WWDC
WWDC to share with you all the
并跟大家分享
new and exciting features around
在 iOS 12 中
user notifications that your
你的 App 可以采用的
applications can start using
一些用户通知方面
with iOS 12.
非常赞的新功能
Today, we will be going over a
今天我们一起来看一下
range of topics as you can see
幻灯片上的
from the list here.
几个主题
We will start with talking about
首先是分组通知
paradigm that we've introduced
这是之前我们在 iOS 用户通知中
to iOS notifications when
添加的新范例
presented in the user's
在用户的通知列表中
notification list.
可以看到分组通知
Then we'll talk about
然后来看一下
notification content extensions,
通知内容扩展
which are existing extension
其中包括
points with notifications, and
现有的通知扩展
discuss new APIs that you've
以及新增的接口
Then, we'll cover notification
下一个主题包括
management and talk about all
通知管理
the new ways in which your
还有针对你的 App
application users can now tweak
用户可以调整的一些
your notification settings and
通知设置
what you need to do to respond
以及你要如何处理
to these new options.
这些新增选项
Then, we'll cover provisional
再然后是
authorization, which allows your
临时授权 这个机制
applications to have a trial
让你的 App 在一段时间内
phase for sending notifications
可以给用户试发送通知
to users without their explicit
无需用户明确允许
permission but do it quietly.
但是也不会有声音提醒
And lastly, we'll cover critical
我们最后一个主题是
alerts, which allows your
重要提醒
applications to send important
此功能让你的 App 可以
notifications to the users,
在用户允许的情况下
which bypass certain system
忽略一些系统设定
settings if your users allows
从而给用户发送
your applications to do so.
重要的提醒
So there's a range of topics to
今天我们
be covered today, and let's
要讲的主题不少
begin with looking at grouped
就让我们先来说说
notifications.
分组通知
Now up to iOS 11, all new
在 iOS 11 及之前版本的系统中
incoming notifications for the
所有新的用户通知
users were inserted in a
都是在通知列表中
chronological order in the
以时间顺序
notification list.
排列显示的
So these would be interspersed
这就造成多个 App 的通知
across multiple applications,
穿插显示
and it would be hard for the
而用户很难
user to find a certain
一下找到某个通知
notification or triage multiple
或分流多个通知
So starting in iOS 12, we've
因此从 iOS 12 起
decided to improve this by
我们决定加以改进
introducing notification
新增分组通知功能
grouping, so now, as you can see
现在大家可以看到
here, all notifications across
多个 App 的
different applications get
各种通知都被分到了
groups.
专属于它们的分组
Let's take a deeper look at how
下面我们仔细谈谈
grouped notifications works.
分组通知
Now all these notifications will
所有通知
be automatically grouped, so
会自动进行分组
there's nothing explicit that
所以你不需要
you need to do to start using
任何操作
notification grouping.
就可以使用该功能
However, if you do want to have
但是如果你想
your own custom groups then you
创建自定义分组
can use the thread identifier,
那就需要使用线程标识
which is an existing property on
线程标识
the UN notification content
是 UN notification content 对象中
object.
已有的属性
So some of you might already be
你们当中可能有人
using the thread identifier and
给本地通知
for a local notification.
加过线程标识
You can set it on the
正如所示 你可以在
UNMutableNotificationContent
UNMutableNotificationContent
object as seen here.
的对象中进行添加
And for a remote notification
而在远程通知的 payload 处
payload, you can also include it
你也可以将
as part of your notification
线程标识添加进去
Now the thread identifier might
现在你们
be familiar to some of you
可能已经比较了解线程标识了
We use it today for forwarding
现在我们用它
notifications to a notification
将通知发送给
content extension that is
App 的
presented for your application,
通知内容扩展
which has the exact same thread
App 必须带有
identifier, allowing the content
同样的线程标识
extension view to update it
才能根据新通知
based on the new incoming
来更新内容扩展视图
Starting in iOS 11, we started
我们从 iOS 11 起
using the thread identifier for
如果用户之前开启了 [ 音质不清晰 ]
doing grouping of notifications,
我们便可以使用线程标识
if the user had turned on
对通知进行分组
So we're just taking this
可以说
concept and expanding it for all
我们拓展了线程标识的运用
notifications in general.
将其覆盖所有类型的通知
So how does this grouping work?
那通知分组是如何实现的呢
So when a new notification comes
你的设备
in to you, the user's device, if
接收到新通知时
there is no thread identifier
如果该通知不包含
set on this notification, then
线程标识
this notifications gets grouped
那这条通知
with the application bundle.
会根据所属 App 进行分组
We can see that from our sample
正如这个例子
application here, that as new
所展示的
notifications are incoming, they
接收到的新通知
are getting bundled with the
都被分到了同一组
same group and the group is
而该分组显示的
getting updated with the latest
是接收到的
content.
最新通知
And then the user can simply
然后用户可以
expand this notification group
轻松展开分组
to see all the notifications
来阅读现有的
that are present in that group.
所有通知
On the other hand, if the
另一方面
notification does have a thread
如果通知带有
identifier set on it, then it
线程标识
gets grouped with all the other
这条通知会与
notifications from that same
相同 App
application with that exact same
且带有同样线程 ID 的通知
thread ID.
分到一组
What this also means is that the
这意味着
same application can then have
相同 App 可以有
multiple different custom
多个自定义的
groups, depending upon the
通知分组
unique thread identifiers that
通过你设置的不同的线程标识
you're setting on them.
进行区分
A good example of this is the
Messages 这个 App
messages application, where here
是一个很好的例子
you can see there are two
大家可以看到
different threads, and as new
这里有两个分组
notifications are incoming, they
当接收到新通知时
are going to their own
新通知会被分到
respective groups.
相对应的分组中
And then the user can expand a
用户可以打开
specific group to see all the
其中一个分组
notifications that are part of
来查看该分组中
that group.
所包含的通知
So by using the thread
所以通过使用线程标识
identifier, messages is able to
messages 也可以
do so.
做到这一点
Now, your application users also
使用你的 App 的用户
have the option of tweaking this
也可以在每个 App 的
notification grouping setting
通知设置页面
from your per application
来修改
notification setting's page.
通知分组的设置
Here, they get three options.
用户有三个选项可以选择
If they choose automatic, then
如果用户选择自动
they get the behavior that we
那他所得到的结果
just described.
我们刚刚讲过
However, the user also has the
然而用户还可以
option of just grouping by
选择只按照 App
application, where the system
进行分组
will ignore your thread
此时系统会忽略
identifier and group all
线程标识
notifications into a single
并将同一个 App 的通知
group.
全部归为一组
And if the user wants the same
如果用户想要
behavior as it exists in iOS 11
iOS 11 的分组方式
today, then they can simply turn
他们现在可以
off grouping for your
关闭分组通知
applications' notifications.
非常简单
So do keep this in mind when
所以要记住
you're creating your own custom
当你创建了自定义分组
groups that they create enough
这个分组
value for users when they
要能在用户
receive your applications'
接收你的 App 的通知时
notifications.
对用户有一定的价值
Now what are the different
下面我们来看看
components of a notification
一个通知组
group?
有哪些部分组成
The content that we show is for
这里显示的内容
the latest notification that was
是该通知组中
received as part of that group.
最新的一条通知
And then the user can simply see
用户只需点击这个分组
all the notifications by tapping
就可以看见其中
on this group, and we expand all
所有的通知
the notifications' content.
通知的内容也同时展开
And then the user can interact
然后用户可以
with all these notifications
单独处理
individually as well.
每一个通知
The two buttons at the top give
上方的两个按钮
the users much greater control
可以让用户更好地
like collapsing the stack as
管理通知
well as clearing all these
比如一键合并分组
notifications together.
或清除该分组的所有通知
Now, notification grouping also
通知分组
makes triaging of notifications
让用户对通知的优先级管理
much better.
变得更容易
For example, in this case, the
举个例子
user can clear all these
如果用户想要
notifications together by simply
清除这些通知
swiping to the right and tapping
只需向左滑动
clear all.
然后点击清除所有即可
Apart from the content of the
除去显示
notification group, we also show
通知组的内容
a summary text.
我们还会显示一行概略文本
Now, this summary text, by
这行概略文本
default, shows the count of all
默认显示
the notifications that are part
该分组中包含的
of that group.
通知数量
However, you can also create a
然而你也可以创建
custom summary text so you can
自定义的概略文本
give your users much better
让用户能
context of what kind of
更好地理解
information is included in that
该通知组中的内容
Now, we will cover this API and
我们会在下一场会议上
go over much larger use cases of
给大家细讲这部分的接口
how you can create your custom
并拓展更多用例
groups in the advanced session
告诉大家
around using group
如何通过分组通知
notifications, which will follow
创建自定义分组
So let's do a quick summary of
现在我给大家
group notifications as we saw
简单总结一下
them today.
分组通知
Starting in iOS 12, all
从 iOS 12 起
application notifications are
所有 App 的通知
going to be grouped
将会被自动分组
You can start using the thread
如果想创建
identifier if you want to create
自定义分组
your own custom groups for your
你需要使用
applications, but the user does
线程标识
have the option of changing this
但是用户
grouping setting for your
可以改变
applications' notifications.
这一分组设定
And lastly, you can use the
最后就是
summary text for customizing the
你可以自定义
information you want to provide
概略文本的内容
the user around the notification
在通知组中
groups that you're creating.
展现给用户
All right, so that was group
以上就是关于
notifications.
分组通知的内容
Now, let's move on to the next
我们的下一个主题
topic and talk about
有关于
notification content extensions.
通知内容扩展
Now, some of you might already
你们当中有些人
be familiar with these content
可能已经比较熟悉
extensions that we included with
iOS 10 中的通知内容扩展了
Content extensions allow your
通知内容扩展
applications to present a rich
可以丰富
notification view around the
App 通知的
user's notifications, so you can
展现形式
have a much more customized and
这样用户看见的
interactive interface for the
是更加量身定制
notification that the user is
交互性也更高的通知
seeing.
我们来简单回顾一下
setting up these content
如何创建
extensions.
通知内容扩展
Xcode gives you a standard
Xcode 中提供了一个
template to add a target for the
标准模板
content extensions to your
让你在你的 App 中
applications and once you set
为通知内容扩展
that up, we create a default
添加一个 target
class for the notification view
一旦你设置好 我们就为通知的 view controller
controller, which implements the
创建了一个默认的类
UNNotificationContentExtension
这个类会执行
protocol.
UNNotificationContentExtension 协议
Here, the did receive
在这里 did receive notification 方法
notification method is important
非常重要
because this is your entry point
因为这是创建
for setting up the view
内容扩展相关视图的
associated with the content
第一步
extension, and you can use the
你可以用
notification object past here to
此处的通知对象
get all the information around
来获取通知的相关信息
that notification to set up your
然后创建你的
custom view.
自定义视图
The info.plist file associated
与内容扩展相关联的
with your content extension
info.plist 文件
gives you more options.
让你有更多选择
The important thing here is the
这里最重要的是
category identifier.
类别标识
Now, this identifier needs to
此处的类别标识
match the same category
需要与你通知请求中的
identifier you're setting on
类别标识
your notification requests
保持一致
because that's how the system
这样系统才知道
knows which content extension to
哪个内容扩展
launch with which notification.
对应哪条通知
Along with this, you can do some
此外 你也可以
quick configurations of your
快速配置
content extension such as
内容扩展
setting the initial content size
例如设置 initial content size ratio
ratio, hiding the default
隐藏默认内容
content, as well as overriding
以及覆盖
the title of this content
该内容扩展的标题
Now, the primary way in which
用户与这些
your users interact with these
内容扩展产生交互的
content extensions is through
主要方式是
notification actions, and these
通知的 action
actions are presented right
这些 action
below the content of the content
显示在内容扩展的内容下方
Let's summarize how we can set
我们也来回顾一下
up these actions as well.
如何创建这些 action 吧
So doing so is fairly trivial in
这一步在代码中非常简单
For example, here, we have two
举个例子
actions here for like and
这里我们有两个 action 点赞和评论
comment, and we create a simple
我们为点赞创建一个简单的
UNNotificationAction for like
UNNotificationAction
and a text input action for
为评论创建一个文字输入 action
And once we've created these
创建完之后
actions, we create a new
我们创建一个
category giving it the same
新的类型
identifier as the content
让它的类型标识
extension where we want these
跟内容扩展的
actions to be presented.
保持一致
And then, we pass it, the two
然后我们提交
new actions that we created.
这两个新创建的 action
Once we've set up this category,
建立好这个类型之后
then we call
我们就可以调用
setNotificationCategories on the
与我们的 class 关联的
UNNotificationCenter object
UNNotificationCenter 对象的
associated with our class,
setNotificationCategories
giving it the new category that
赋予它我们创建的新类型
So by simply doing so, the next
通过这个简单方法
time when the user goes to your
下次用户碰到
content extension we can see
你的内容扩展时
that these actions are now
用户可以通过这些 action
available for them to interact
与你的通知内容
with your notification content.
进行交互
Now let's take a look at how we
下面我们看一下
can handle the responses from
如何处理从这些 action 中
these actions.
得到的响应
There are two ways to do that.
有两种方式
Firstly, you can handle this
第一个
response in the AppDelegate that
你可以在 App 关联的
is associated with your
AppDelegate（App 委托）中进行处理
application that implements the
App 需要执行
UNUserNotificationCenter
UNUserNotificationCenter 的授权协议
Here, the function
在这里
UserNotificationCenter did
UserNotificationCenter
receive response, includes the
接收到响应
response object which includes
其中包括
information about the request,
请求的信息
the notification request from
和用户行为的
which the user took this action.
通知请求
However, the content extension
然而内容扩展
also allows you to intercept
也可以让你
this action response so that you
拦截这个 action 的响应
can update your view and make a
这样你就可以运用内容扩展
much more interactive and
来更新视图
dynamic experience for users for
并创建一个更具交互性的
the content extension.
动态用户体验
So for our sample here, we enter
在这个示例中
the did receive response method
我们输入了 did receive response 方法
and checked the action
并对点赞这个动作
identifier for the like action.
进行检测
And then we update our UI with
然后我们用新的 label
the new label as well as update
更新 UI
our application state.
也更新 App 状态
Finally calling the completion
最后调用 completion
block we do not dismiss.
设为 do not dismiss
If you do want to dismiss your
如果你想要在此处
content extension view here,
忽略内容扩展视图
then you can simply change the
那么你只需将
parameter you're passing to the
传送给 completion 的
completion block to dismiss or
参数设为 dismiss 或
dismiss and forward, where we
dismiss and forward
will forward this response to
后者会将响应发送给
your AppDelegate function as
AppDelegate（App 委托）
well.
这个功能创建完毕后
this up, we can see that when
我们可以看到
the user takes the like action,
当用户点赞时
the content extension content
内容扩展
gets updated right there and
可以即时得到更新
So it's a much more interactive
这种方式增强了
experience for your user and
用户交互
they're getting real-time
他们也可以得到
feedback.
即时反馈
However, if you look at the
但是如果观察
current state of the content
内容扩展的当前状态
extension, we see that there is
我们会发现一些
some redundant information.
冗余的信息
The user has already taken the
用户点赞后
like action, so having the
再保留
action there doesn't really
点赞这个 action
serve a purpose anymore.
就没有意义了
Now notification actions, in
通常来说
general, have certain
通知 action
limitations.
有一定局限
They are not very dynamic and
通知不太具有动态
can't be updated based on the
也无法根据
context of your content
内容扩展的场景
extensions.
进行更新
Also, these tend to be tied to
还有就是这些情况
the notification categories that
与通知的类型有关联
you have to define at the time
而通知的类型在创建 App 时
of your application setup.
必须定义好
So we wanted to address these
我们想解决这个问题
issues and we have introduced a
所以新增了一个
new API around notification
通知 action 的接口
actions, where now we're
有了这个接口
exposing these notification
我们就将通知 action
actions as part of the
纳入
NSExtensionContext tied to your
NSExtensionContext
content extension.
从而绑定内容扩展
What this API allows you to do
这个接口
is access the currently
让你可以访问
presented notification actions
现阶段面向用户的
to the user as well as replace
通知 action
these actions by setting a brand
也可以通过
new array of notification
为内容扩展建立
actions for your content
全新的通知 action 数组进行替换
extension.
我们再来看示例
what if after the user took the
如果用户点赞后
like action we wanted to replace
我们想将点赞的 action
it say with the unlike action so
替换成撤销点赞的 action
that they can do the reverse of
怎么让用户可以对刚才的操作
the action they just took?
进行反向操作呢
So using this new API, let's
我们看一下
take a look of how we can set
如何用新的接口
this up.
进行设置
So we go back to our did receive
我们回到 did receive response 方法
response method and again
再一次识别
identify the like action and
点赞行为
update our application state.
并更新我们的 App 状态
This time, we also create a new
这一次我们还创建了
action for unlike, giving it a
一个新的撤销点赞的 action
unique identifier as well as a
给它添加一个独有的标识和标题
We can also take a look at the
我们可以再看一下
currently presented actions so
现有的 action
that we can extract the comment
这样就可以提取
action from there without having
评论的 action
to create it again.
而不用再次创建
Then we create a new array of
然后我们创建一个
these new actions that we've
新 action 的数组
created and simply set that on
将数组设为
the notification actions
通知 action 的变量就可以了
So once we've done this and the
这步完成后
user takes the like action, then
用户点赞之后
the UI will automatically update
UI 会自动变化
to show them the new action, and
展示新的 action
then the user can then toggle
然后用户可以再在
between the two actions,
两个 action 中进行选择
depending upon how you handle
这取决于你如何
that state in your content
在内容扩展中
extensions.
处理状态
Now, this API can be used in
这个接口
multiple other ways as well.
还有其他多个用法
For example, now you can set
例如
your actions at the time you're
在 did receive notification 方法中
setting up your content
你可以在
extension view in the did
创建内容扩展视图的同时
receive notification method.
创建你的 action
What this means is your
这意味着
notification requests are no
你的通知请求
longer tied to the category to
在定义
define the actions that you want
通知的 action 时
to present around these
不再与类型绑定在一起
You can also now present a
现在你还可以
secondary set of actions by
展示二级 action
replacing the currently
只要将当前 action 替换掉就可以了
For example, if the leading
例如
action was rate, then you can
如果首发 action 是评分
provide a secondary list of the
下面你就可以建立一个
different types of ratings that
包含不同评分类型的二级列表
you want your user to take.
以供用户选择
And you can also remove all
如果你认为
these notification actions if
内容扩展没有必要
you feel it does not make sense
再显示这些 action 了
anymore for your content
你可以
extension to present these
将它们去掉
So that's the new API around
这就是通知动作的新接口
And we feel this will really
我们认为
help you enhance the experience
这可以大大增强
that your users have around your
你的内容扩展的
content extensions with the
用户体验
different actions now you can
因为现在你可以 展示给用户多个选择
Let's move on and talk about
我们来看下一个主题
user interaction with these
内容扩展的
content extensions.
用户交互
Now notification actions were
到目前为止
important up till this point
通知 action 很重要
because till iOS 11 we did not
因为 iOS 11 以前
allow user interaction touches
我们不允许在
with your content extension
内容扩展视图中进行用户交互
view.
我们收到了
feedback around this.
很多相关反馈
And I'm happy to announce that
而我现在很高兴地宣布
we're taking away this
我们在 iOS 12 中
restriction with iOS 12.
去掉了这项限制
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
So now your content extensions
现在你在内容扩展中
have the option of opting in to
可以选择
receiving user interaction
通过点触
[inaudible] touches, and setting
接收用户交互
this up, it's fairly trivial.
设置这个功能也很简单
All you have to do is add a new
你只需在
key value option to your
info.plist 文件中
info.plist file.
增添一个键值项
And the key that we've added is
也就是
the UNNotificationExtensionUser
UNNotificationExtensionUser
InteractionEnabled.
InteractionEnabled
So going back to our sample,
再来看示例
what if we want to remove the
如果我们想要
like action from a notification
去掉点赞这个 action
action and make it a UI
将其改成
interaction touch that's part of
融于视图的
the view itself?
UI 点触交互
So once we've configured our
我们再次配置
info.plist file, we can go back
info.plist 文件
to our content extension view
我们可以回到内容扩展视图
and create our own custom button
创建自定义按钮
to handle the like gesture.
来接收点赞
We add a target for our own
我们在私有方法中添加了一个 target
private method and inside that
在这个函数中
function, we update the UI as
我们更新了 UI
well as update our application
还有 App 的状态
So here, it's important that
这里需要注意
since you're implementing your
由于你在执行
own user interactions that you
自定义的交互
are responsible for handling all
你要负责处理
these actions, responses, and
所有用户的 action
callbacks from the users
response
yourself.
和 callback
So once we've set this up, now
这部分完成后
when the user goes to your
用户看到你的内容扩展时
content extension we see the
就可以看见
Like button, part of the UI
这个点赞按钮
itself, and the user can simply
它是 UI 中的一部分
interact with that button right
用户可以即时点击按钮 完成交互
So that's the new functionality
这个就是我们为
that we've added around content
内容扩展添加的新功能
And coupled with notification
有了这个功能
actions, along with user
再加上通知 action
interaction touches, you now
还有用户交互点触
have a much richer set of tools
你就可以利用这一组
interactive and dynamic content
丰富的工具
extension experiences for your
给你的 App 通知的用户
applications notifications
带来更具交互性的
users.
动态内容扩展体验
Now let's talk about launching
接下来是
your application from the
通过通知内容扩展
notification content extension.
启动 App
So today the user can launch
现在 即使没有点触位置
your application if touches were
用户只需点击
not allowed by simply tapping
内容扩展视图
the content extension view.
就可以轻松打开 App
They could also do so by tapping
用户也可以点击
your application icon in the top
通知左上角的
left corner.
App 图标
Or you could create a foreground
或者你可以创建一个
action, which then would in turn
foreground action
launch the application.
让用户打开 App
But what if you wanted to do
那我们如何能
this from your own custom
自定义启动 App 的控制呢
What if you wanted to launch the
如果你想通过代码启动
application programmatically?
要怎么做呢
To enable this, there is a new
使用 NSExtensionContext
API on the NSExtensionContext
的一个新接口
called performNotification
就可以做到这点
DefaultAction, which would allow
这个接口是 performNotification
you to do this now.
DefaultAction
Now, what does the default
那么 default action 是什么呢
So, as we said, it launches the
刚才说过 default action
application, but at the same
可以启动 App
time, it calls the
但是同时
UserNotificationCenter did
会在 App 委托
receive response method in your
调用 UserNotificationCenter 的
application delegate.
did receive response 方法
Now the UNNotificationResponse
UNNotificationResponse 的对象
object contains the information
记录用户
of the notification from which
是从哪条通知
the user came, so you can update
点进来的
your application state based on
这样你就可以根据通知
the notification.
更新 App 状态
And the identifier that's passed
这里使用的
here is the
标识符是 UNNotificationDefault
ActionIdentifier.
ActionIdentifier
So going back to our sample,
让我们通过示例
let's see how we can set this
看一下如何设置
custom control up.
自定义的启动控制
Now again, we create our own UI
现在我们创建了 UI 按钮
button for the all comments and
以显示所有评论
then tie it up with our own
然后与我们的私有功能
private function.
进行绑定
And in that function, we're
在这个功能里
simply calling
我们只需调用
PerformNotification
PerformNotification
DefaultAction.
DefaultAction
So by simply doing that, you get
这样的话
this functionality to call this
此功能就可以
method programmatically from
在内容扩展的代码中
anywhere in your content
自动调用
extension code.
这个方法
So that was launching the
这部分是关于启动 App 的内容
What about dismissing the
如何解除内容扩展视图呢
Again, let's take a look at how
我们再来看看
the user can do that today.
现在用户可以如何实现这一点
They can do that by tapping the
用户可以点击
Dismiss Button in the top right
右上角的退出按钮
corner, or you can create your
或者你可以
own custom notification action,
自定义通知 action
which would in turn dismiss the
同样可以退出
content extension view.
内容扩展视图
Which you can set up, as we saw
我们之前讲过如何创建
before, by passing dismiss to
那就是向 completion block
the completion block.
传递退出请求
But again, what if we want to
如果我们想
dismiss the view through our own
通过自定义按钮
custom buttons, and we want to
退出视图
do this programmatically?
我们如何通过代码实现呢
Say that when the user taps the
假设用户点击
Like button, then the view
点赞按钮
dismisses because we feel the
视图会退出
user's done interacting with the
因为我们认为用户已经完成
content extension.
与内容扩展的交互
To enable this as well, there's
为了实现这一点
a new API called
我们设了一个新接口
dismissNotificationContent
dismissNotification
Extension that's on the
ContentExtension
NSExtensionContext.
它归属 NSExtensionContext
We go back to how we set up our
让我们回到创建点赞按钮处
Like button, and now this time,
这一次
we also call the new function
我们一同调用
that we added for dismissing the
退出内容扩展视图的
content extension view.
新功能
And once we set this up, now
创建好后
when the user takes the like
当用户触发点赞
action, the view of the content
内容扩展的视图
extension gets dismissed.
会直接退出
Now one thing to note here.
需要注意的一点是
That calling this method does
调用这个方法
not withdraw the notification
并不会撤回
that was posted to the user.
推送给用户的通知
If you want to do that then use
如果你想要撤回通知
the existing API for removing
就需要使用现有的接口
delivered notifications with
移除已发送的通知
identifiers to get that
你需要使用标识符
functionality.
才能使用这个功能
All right, now let's summarize
现在让我们总结一下
all the new APIs that we've
今天介绍的
looked at today around the
所有通知内容扩展的
notification content extensions.
新接口
We started with talking about
首先是
notification actions where now
通知 action
you can access these
你可以访问
replace them dynamically from
也可以在你的
anywhere in your content
内容扩展代码中
extension code.
将其动态替换掉
You can now opt in to having
你现在可以选择 在内容扩展视图中
touches within your content
创建可点触的
extension views.
用户交互体验
You can programmatically launch
你还可以通过内容扩展的代码
your content extension code as
自动启动 App
well as dismiss the content
或退出
extension view, depending upon
内容扩展视图
where you feel it serves best
你需要根据内容扩展的
your user's experience around
用户体验需求进行选择
So that's a varied list of APIs
这些就是
around content extensions, and
内容扩展的
we hope this really helps you
几个新的接口
enhance your user's experience
希望使用后
around your content extensions
可以帮助大家
and then you start using these
增强内容扩展的
APIs.
用户体验
So that was notification content
这些就是通知内容扩展的
extensions.
相关内容
Now, the next topic today we're
我们今天的
going to look at is notification
下一个主题是
management, and to tell you all
通知管理
about that, let me invite my
现在欢迎
colleague Teja to the stage.
我的同事 Teja 上台
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Kritarth.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Kritarth
Hi everyone.
大家好
My name is Teja Kondapalli, and
我是 Teja Kondapalli
I'm also an engineer on the iOS
我也是 iOS 通知团队的
Notifications' Team.
一名工程师
And, of course, I'm here to talk
下面由我
to you about a couple of the new
给大家介绍几个
APIs that we have.
新的接口
The first of which is
第一个是
notification management.
通知管理
But before I dive into this API,
但是在我深入讲解前
I want to cover some of the user
我想先介绍几个
facing features to give you some
面向用户的功能
more context and then we can
给大家一些背景知识
deep dive into the API.
然后再让我们深入了解这些接口
As our users get more and more
现在 用户手机上的
apps on their phones,
App 越来越多
notifications become the primary
通知是用户与 App 产生交互的
these apps.
主要方式
But often, they find themselves
然而通常
in a situation like this.
用户会陷入这样一种情况
With far too many notifications.
那就是通知过多
And it becomes hard to sift
筛选
through and find the important
重要通知
ones.
变得非常困难
So perhaps to make this easier,
为了减负
this user has decided that
有些用户认为
notifications from podcasts
播客的通知
don't need to be shown on the
无需在锁屏处显示
Right now to configure that
如果想要进行调整
they'd have to launch the
用户需要
settings app, find
打开设置
notifications, find the podcast
在通知里
app, and then they can configure
找到播客
their settings.
再修改设置
We wanted to make this easier.
我们想要缓解这个状况
So, in iOS 12, we're introducing
所以在 iOS 12 中
a new management view where the
新增了管理视图
users can configure their
用户可以直接
notification settings directly
在接收通知的地方
from the notification without
调整通知设置
having to launch the settings
无需到设置中调整
There's three really easy ways
有三个简单的方式
to get into this management
可以进入通知管理视图
The first is what we just saw.
第一个我们刚才已经看过
You simply swipe over a
你只需将通知向左滑
notification, tap manage, and
点击管理
the management view comes up.
管理视图就会出现
The second is if you can go into
第二个方式
the rich notification, you can
打开通知组
tap in the right corner, and you
点击右上角
can also launch the management
你也可以打开管理视图
And the third is actually in the
第三种方式会出现在
list itself.
列表中
Depending on how your users are
这取决于用户与
interacting with their
通知之间的交互
notifications, they will
用户有时会看到
occasionally see suggestions,
管理建议
like this one, that ask them if
就像这个一样
they want to keep receiving
会询问用户是否保留
podcast notifications.
播客的通知
And from here, as well, they can
在这里
tap manage and bring up the
用户可以点击管理
management view.
进入管理视图
Let's take a closer look at the
下面我们来仔细看一下
And we obviously have options
非常明显
here where users can configure
用户可以自行
their notification settings
在这个视图中直接修改
directly from this view.
通知设置
But if they want to go into the
如果用户想要
settings app and configure in a
在设置里
more detailed manner, they have
做更详细的修改
a quick link to the settings for
可以通过设置按钮
this application, the
更快地打开
notification settings.
设置程序
A And also from this view, they
在这处视图
have some actions they can take
有一些操作用户可以直接操作
directly, the first of which
一个是 通知静音
probably a concept that's new to
这个对于大家来说
all of you.
可能比较陌生
Some of these management views
有时管理视图
will also have an option that
会显示优先发送
let's talk about what this
我们来看看 这是什么
means.
在 iOS 中
settings that users can
有很多设置用户都可以修改
configure, and this is really
对于比较玩得转的用户来说
great for the power user.
这是一大优点
The can customize their settings
他们可以自行修改设置
to every detail, but for the
精确到细节
regular user, we think that we
但是对于普通用户来说
can help them out by
我们就需要
categorizing their notification
协助他们
settings into two big
将通知设置分成
categories.
两大类
Notifications that are delivered
一是
prominently and notifications
优先发送的通知
that are delivered quietly.
二是静音发送的通知
Notifications that are delivered
我们比较熟悉优先发送的通知
They show up on the locked
这类通知
screen.
出现在我们的锁屏上
They show up in notification
出现在
center.
Notification Center
They roll down as banners.
也会以横幅的形式出现
They badge the AP icon and they
或在 App 图标上生成角标
can play a sound.
也有声音提示
Notifications that are delivered
静音发送的通知
quietly only show up in
只会显示在
notification center and they
Notification Center 中
don't play a sound.
并且没有声音提示
And from the management view, in
在管理视图中
addition to configuring whether
除了可以设置
they want their notifications
优先发送通知
delivered prominently or
和静音通知
quietly, users also have the
用户还可以
option to turn off their
选择关闭通知
Now, I know that you might worry
我知道现在大家
that your users are going to
担心用户会关闭
turn off the notifications for
你的 App 通知
your app, so we've added this
所以我们
extra confirmation sheet just in
增加了一步确认
case they do tap turn off.
以防用户误点
And from here, they can also
用户在这里
turn off their notifications.
也可以关闭通知
But we've also added an API to
我们还新增了一个接口
add a second option to this
可以在确认窗口添加
confirmation sheet, and podcast
另一个选项
has taken advantage of this API,
播客就使用了这个接口
so it says configure in podcast.
所以这里显示去播客中设置
This is a link that will deep
这个地方
link within the podcast app to a
链接到播客 App 内部的
custom settings view that allows
自定义设置视图
the user more granular control
用户可以更细致地设置
about what kind of podcast
想要接收哪个播客
notifications they want.
的通知
And as your apps send more and
当你的 App 通知
more notifications and various
数量越来越多
type of notifications, we think
类型越来越丰富时
it's really important to allow
让用户可以细致地
control over what kind of
管理什么通知是重要的
notifications are important to
对他们来说很重要
This link can also be accessed
这个链接也可以
from the systems settings app
从系统设置访问
from your apps' notification
只需进入你的 App 的
settings.
通知设置就可以找到
And you can see for podcasts
对于播客来说
it's right at the bottom.
这个链接在页面的下方
It says podcast notifications
名称是播客通知设置
Let's see how we do this in
下面我们看看
code.
这些如何在代码中实现
In the class that conforms to
在 UNUserNotificationCenter
UNUserNotificationCenter
Delegate 这个 class 中
Delegate, we have a new delegate
我们新增了一个委托方法
Open settings for notification,
也就是 openSettingsFor notification
and as long as you implement
只要你执行
this delegate method, those
这个委托方法
links that we talked about from
刚才我们提到
the management view, or from the
管理视图和系统设置中
settings app, will automatically
管理视图的链接
be populated by the system for
系统会自动将其扩充
So when the user taps on any of
所以当用户点击
these links, this delegate
这些链接时
method will be called.
就会调用这个委托方法
And it's really important when
重要的是
this delegate method is called
调用这个委托方法时
that you immediately take your
你必须立即给用户展示
users into the view where they
可以在 App 内
can configure their notification
调整通知设置的
settings within your app.
管理视图
And if you notice, we have
有人可能注意到
[inaudible] parameter to this
我们给这个方法增加了一个参数
method, and it is notification.
叫做 notification
So depending on where the link
链接在不同地方触发
was tapped from, if it was
会有不同影响
tapped from one of the
如果是在某个管理视图
the value of the notification
链接会包含
that that management view came
该 notification 参数的值
If it was tapped from the
如果在
settings app, the value of
系统设置中触发
notification will be nil, and
则 notification 参数的值为空
you can use this information to
你可以在这个委托方法
show the appropriate
被调用时
notification settings when this
显示合适的
delegate method is called.
通知设置
So that's what we have for
这些就是
notification management.
通知管理部分的内容
It's a new way for your users to
对于用户来说
configure whether they want
这是一个新的方式
their notifications delivered
可以设置重点发送或静音发送
prominently or quietly, or turn
关闭通知
them off, or even configure them
甚至可以在 App 中
at a granular level within your
更细致地进行设置
app.
为了鼓励用户
keep getting your notifications
持续接收你的通知
important that you make the
我们认为很重要的一点是
content in the notifications
你的通知
relevant.
要切题
We also encourage you to use
我们也鼓励大家
thread identifiers to group the
使用线程标识
notifications when you think
在适当的时候
it's appropriate.
将通知分组
This will help the users
这可以帮助用户
organize their lists better and
更好地管理通知列表
will make sure that they're not
也确保他们
overwhelmed by the notifications
看到你的 App 通知时
from your app.
不会觉得无从下手
We also think that as your apps
我们还认为
send various types of
如果你的 App
notifications, it's really
会发送多个类型的通知
important to provide that custom
你最好能在 App 中
settings view within that app so
提供自定义设置视图
that users have more granular
这样用户可以
control about what kind of
更细致地管理
notifications are important to
哪种通知对他们最重要
That's what we have for
以上就是
notification management.
通知管理
And the next big feature I want
下面我想介绍的
to talk to you about is
一个比较大的功能
provisional authorization.
就是临时授权
Right now, when a user installs
现在 如果一个用户安装了你的 App
receiving notifications, at some
在他开始接收通知前
point they'll have to respond to
必须回应
a prompt that looks like this,
这样的一个提示
which is asking them if they
提示会询问用户
want these notifications.
是否想接收通知
And the biggest problem with
这最大的问题是
this is, at this point, the user
现在用户
doesn't know what kind of
无法判断
notifications this app is going
App 会发送哪种通知
to send, so they don't know if
所以他们也不知道
they want them or not.
是否想要接收
So, in iOS 12, we're introducing
在 iOS 12 中
provisional authorization, and
我们新增了临时授权
this is an automatic trial of
你的 App 会自动
the notifications from your app.
试发送通知
This will help your users make a
这可以帮助你的用户
more informed decision on
更好地判断
whether they want these
他们是否需要
notifications or not.
这些通知
So you can opt into this, and if
你可以选择使用这个功能
you do, your users will not get
使用后
that authorization prompt that
你的用户就不会收到
we just saw.
我们刚才看到的授权提示了
Instead, the notifications from
相反 你的通知
start getting delivered.
会开始自动推送
But these notifications will be
但是这些通知
delivered quietly, and if we
都没有声音提示
recall, notifications that are
并且 静音发送的通知
in notifications center, and
只会显示在 Notifications Center
they don't play a sound.
这些通知是无声的
Notifications that are delivered
通过临时授权
with provisional authorization
发送的通知
will have a prompt like this on
都会带有这样的提示
And this will help the users
在接收了几条通知后
decide after having received a
可以帮助用户决定
few notifications whether they
是否要继续接收
want to keep getting these
这些通知
notifications or whether they
还是决定
want to turn them off.
关闭通知
And this turn off confirmation
在确认关闭的位置
sheet will also have the custom
如果你创建了
settings link if you have
自定义设置
provided it.
在这里它依然会出现
Let's see how you can do this in
我们来看看
code.
如何通过代码实现
In the location where you
在你通常
regularly request authorization,
请求授权的位置
in addition to whatever options
除了请求的 option
add a dot qualifying option
你还可以添加一个限定 option
called .provisional.
.provisional
And if you include this, you
添加这个以后
will automatically start
你的 App
participating in the trial.
自动加入通知试发送
It's really important to note
大家需要注意
that the .provisional option is
除 .provisional option 外
in addition to whatever other
你还需要有
options you may be providing.
其他的 option
That's because if the users
这是因为如果用户
decide to keep getting your
决定继续接收
notifications delivered, we want
你的通知
to know how you want them
系统必须知道
delivered, with badges or sounds
你想如何发送
or as alerts.
是否要角标 声音 还是作为提醒
So that's what provisional
这就是临时授权
It's an automatic trial of the
它是自动的
notifications from your app to
通知试发送
help your users make a more
可以帮助你的用户
informed decision about whether
更好地决定
they want these notifications.
是否要继续接收你的通知
And again, to encourage your
同样 为了鼓励用户
notifications delivered, it's
继续接收
really important to make the
你的通知内容
content in your notifications
一定要与你的 App 相关
And also, it's really important
并且要记住一点
qualifier option in addition to
使用 .provisional 作为预选项时
whatever other options you're
还需要有其他
requesting.
你请求的 option
That's what we have for
这就是临时授权
provisional authorization.
的全部内容
And the last big feature that I
我想介绍的
want to talk to you about are
最后一个大的功能
critical alerts.
就是重要提醒
Often when I'm in the middle of
通常在我参加会议
important, my phone looks like
或有重要的事情时
this.
我的手机是这样的
And as you can see, I have do
大家可以看到
not disturb turned on.
我开启了免打扰模式
Or at least I have the ringer
或者 我至少会
switch turned off so that I
关闭铃声
don't hear any sounds when I get
这样我接收通知时
notifications.
就不会有声音提示
And usually this is really good,
通常来说 这样很好
but I would have missed a really
但是我可能会错过
important notification like this
非常重要的通知
one.
就像这个 这是一条
notification.
与健康相关的通知
That's from a glucose monitor
我的血糖仪提醒我
that's warning me of low blood
我的血糖过低
sugar, and this is something I
这样的通知
would want to see immediately.
我会希望能及时看到
Scenarios like this made us
这样的场景
realize that we need a new type
让我们意识到
of notification, and this is
我们需要一类新的通知
what we call critical alerts.
我们将它称为重要提醒
Critical alerts are medical- and
重要提醒是
health-related notifications.
医药 健康
Or home- and security-related
家庭 安全
notifications.
或公共安全
Or public safety notifications.
相关的通知
And the key to a critical alert
重要提醒的关键
is that it requires the user to
在于需要用户
take action immediately.
马上做出回应
The way that critical alerts
重要提醒
behave is that they bypass both
可以忽略
do not disturb and the ringer
免打扰模式
switch, and they will play a
和铃声静音
sound.
发出声音提示 你甚至可以
But what that means is that
但是这也意味着
these are very disruptive, and
重要提醒会产生干扰
for that reason we don't think
因为这一点
that all apps should be able to
我们认为不能允许所有的 App
send critical notifications.
发送重要提醒
So in order to start sending a
想要发送重要提醒
critical alert, you will need to
首先你需要
apply for entitlement, and you
申请授权
can do that on the
你可以登录
developer.apple website.
developer.apple 的网站申请
This is what a critical alert
重要提醒
looks like, and you can see that
是这个样子
it has a unique icon indicating
有一个独特的图标
that it's critical.
表示其重要性
And it would have also come in
接收重要提醒时 还会有声音提示
Critical alerts also have their
在通知设置中
own section in notifications
重要提醒 可单独进行设置
This means that a user can
这表示 用户可以允许某个 App
for a particular application but
发送重要提醒
choose not to allow any other
但是不允许接收该 App
type of notification.
其他类型的通知
And before users start receiving
接收重要提醒之前
critical alerts, they will have
用户需要
to accept a prompt that looks
通过这样的
like this that's asking them
一个提示
specifically whether they want
询问他们
to accept critical alerts from a
是否想要接收某个 App 的
particular application.
重要提醒
So, of course, in order to start
所以 在发送重要提醒前
have to request authorization.
你当然需要获得授权
So after you apply for
当你的
entitlement and get it, in the
授权申请通过后
place where you regularly
在你通常请求授权
request authorization, in
请求授权的位置
addition to whatever other
除了其他
options you want to request, you
需要请求的 option
can also request a
你还可以请求
.criticalAlert option.
.criticalAlert option
And this will give your users
用户会先看到提示
And let's see how it actually
下面我们看看
set up and send a critical
如何创建和发送重要提醒
alert.
其实重要提醒
similarly to a regular
和普通通知的
notification.
原理相近
You can see that I just set up a
可以看到
notification with the title body
我创建了一个通知
and category identifier, but
带有标题 主体 和类型标识
what distinguishes this as a
但是最独特的一点是
critical alert is that it plays
重要提醒
a sound.
有声音提示
So I need to set a critical
所以我需要设置
alert sound.
重要提醒的提示音
And here, you can see that I'm
大家可以看到
setting the default critical
我设置的是
alert sound that's provided by
重要提醒的默认提示音
the framework.
由框架提供
I can also set a custom sound.
我还可以自定义提示音
And I can also set a custom
还可以自定义
audio volume level.
提示音量
And of course, critical alerts
当然
can also be push notifications
重要提醒也可以是推送通知
so all of this information can
这样所有的这些信息
be set in the push payload as
可以在 push payload 中进行创建
So that's what we have for
这就是重要提醒
They're a new type of
它是新类型的通知
users to take action
需要用户及时回应
And they're very disruptive, so
重要提醒会产生干扰
you need entitlement to be able
所以你需要得到授权 才可以发送
So that's all the new exciting
这就是今天要给大家介绍的
APIs that we have for you today.
所有新的接口
I just want to quickly go over
我来很快给大家总结一下
all the things that we covered.
今天的主要内容
We talked about how you can use
我们介绍了如何
thread identifiers to group your
使用线程标识对通知分组
notifications to help your users
对通知分组
organize their notification
以帮助用户
lists better.
更好地管理通知列表
We talked about all the great
我们介绍了
new APIs around notification
通知内容扩展的
content extensions, which will
全新接口
help you make your rich
可以让你的通知
notifications much more
变得更具交互性
We talked about how you can
我们还谈到
provide a custom settings view
如何在你的 App 中
within your app to allow your
创建自定义设置视图
users more granular control over
让用户可以更精细地
what kind of notifications they
筛选想要保留
want to receive.
哪些通知
We also talked about provisional
再然后是
authorizations, which is an
临时授权
automatic trial of the
让你的 App
notifications from your app,
可以自动试发送通知
which will help you users make a
这样你的用户
more informed decision about
可以更好地决定
whether they want these
是否要保留
notifications or not.
你的通知
And last, we talked about
最后我们介绍了
critical alerts, which are a new
重要提醒
type of notification that
这是新的一类通知
requires the user to take action
需要用户采取
immediately and that are
及时回应
disruptive.
还会产生干扰
So we hope you take advantage of
我们希望你们可以利用好
all of these great APIs and make
这些非常棒的接口
the notification experience for
给你们的用户
your users even better.
带来更好的通知用户体验
You can find all the information
有关本次会议的
about this session on our
所有信息
sessions' page at
可以在会议页面看到
developer.apple.com.
developer.apple.com
We're session 710.
我们的会议号码是 710
We have another session just
接下来还有一次会议
following this one in hall three
在三号大厅举行
called using grouped
内容是如何使用
notification where we'll help
分组通知
you determine how to best group
我们会帮助大家决定
notifications for your app.
如何将你的通知分组最有效
We have two notifications labs,
我们有两个通知实验议程
one today and one tomorrow,
一个在今天 一个在明天
where you can come and ask the
你可以向我们团队的
engineers on our team any
工程师询问
questions that you may have.
任何相关问题
And on Friday morning, we have
周五上午
an interesting session called
我们还有一场非常有趣的会议
designing notifications.
叫做如何设计通知
That's going to be hosted by the
讲者是我们的设计师
with the designs for these, and
他们帮助我们设计了所有的这些
they'll be talking about
到时候他们会介绍
notification best practices.
通知的最佳使用方法
Thank you and have a great dot
感谢大家 祝大家顺利
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]